ABHISHEK JAMWAL

Phone: 365-778-7384 | Email: jamwalab@live.com | Mississauga, ON, L5E 2L2

LinkedIn GitHub Portfolio

www.linkedin.com/in/abhishekj-21 www.github.com/jamwalab https://jamwalab.github.io/abhishek

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer, with a certificate from the University of Toronto. Experience in back-end design, database management, and creating automated solutions. A team player, with good communication and problem-solving skills. Passionate about programming, with a strong ability to design, build and maintain websites from ideation to production. An eager learner, with seven years of experience working in the Supply Chain Industry.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, Visual Basic Application (VBA), Python

Applications: GitHub, MongoDB (NoSQL), MySQL, AWS

Tools: Express, React, Node, Handlebars, jQuery, Bootstrap, API, PWA, OOP

PROJECTS

Smart-Fix

github.com/groupsixzerotwo/smart-fix | https://floating-cove-91289.herokuapp.com

Tools - HTML, CSS, Node, Express, MySQL, API, Handlebars, JavaScript

Summary - Helps customers connect with service providers for household repairs and maintenance. Allows users to register as a customer or service provider, with different functionality based on user type.

ETA Tracker

github.com/jamwalab/checkEta | https://hidden-cliffs-50551.herokuapp.com

Tools - HTML, CSS, Node, Express, MySQL, API, Handlebars, JavaScript

Summary - Helps provide an estimated time of arrival for shipments arriving at the port and moving on the rail. Allows users to request eta of shipping containers in bulk and display results in a table.

Calorie Tracker

github.com/uot-project-grp/project01-calorie-tracker | https://uot-project-grp.github.io/project01-calorie-tracker | Tools - HTML, CSS, JavaScript, API

Summary - Allows users to set calorie targets, track daily calorie consumption, and track consumption with tables and graphs. Users can search food items for calorie data and recipes or manually add consumption data.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Maersk | Associate - Customs House Brokerage | Mississauga, ON, Canada | September 2018 - Present

- Reduced the time required to track shipments by half, allowing containers to be searched in bulk with ETA Tracker.
- Designed a VBA macro that automatically tracks shipments for customs release and assigns status at various stages of customs clearance.
- Built a VBA macro that checks entries filed with Canadian customs daily to match customer requirements, thus
 achieving an accuracy of over 97%.

APL Logistics | Senior Analyst - Global Trade Compliance | Gurgaon, India | July 2016 - June 2018

• Developed and maintained trade compliance database for multiple countries with MySQL, XML, and Excel.

- Built a VBA macro that successfully reduced the time required to compile data for the database by 80%.
- Assisted in the design and testing of the Trade Compliance website.

Molex | Analyst – Trade and Customs | Bangalore, India | August 2015 – June 2016

• Maintained HS code database of the products on SAP system for various countries.

Aptean | Analyst – Global Trade Content | Bangalore, India | February 2014 – August 2015

- Designed backend process to capture trade compliance data from customs websites of different countries.
- Analyze customs laws and regulations for international trade and prepare regular content updates for the Global Trade Management (TradeBeam) database.
- Run thorough quality assurance of the changes on the test server before moving the code to production.

EDUCATION

Certificate – Full Stack Web Development | University of Toronto | Toronto, ON, Canada

Bachelor of Engineering - Electronics and Telecommunication | University of Mumbai | Mumbai, India

Post Graduate Diploma in Management | Birla Institute of Management Technology | Greater Noida, India

CERTIFICATION

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner | Amazon Web Services